Chapter 20. All a stir.
A day or two passed, and there was great activity aboard the Peekquad. Not only
were the old sails being mended, but new sails were coming on board, and bolts of
canvas and coils of rigging. In short, everything be token that the ship's
preparations were hurrying to a close.
Captain Pelleg seldom or never went ashore, but sat in his wigwam, keeping a
sharp lookout upon the hands. Bildad did all the purchasing and providing at the
stores, and the men employed in the hold and on the rigging were working till
long after nightfall.
On the day following Quequ signing the articles, word was given at all the inns
where the ship's company were stopping that their chests must be on board
before night, for there was no telling how soon the vessel might be sailing. So
Quiquig got down our traps, resolving, however, to sleep ashore till the last.
But it seems they always give very long notice in these cases, and the ship did
not sail for several days. But no wonder there was a good deal to be done, and
there is no telling how many things to be thought of before the Peekquad was
fully equipped. Everyone knows what a multitude of things, beds, saucepans,
knives, and forks, shovels, and tongs, napkins, nutcrackers, and whatnot, are
indispensable to the business of housekeeping. Just so with whailing,
which necessitates a three years housekeeping upon the wide ocean, far
from all grocerers, coaster mongers, doctors, bakers, and bankers. And though
this also holds true of merchant vessels, yet not by any means to the
same extent as with whalemen, for besides the great length of the whailing
voyage, the numerous articles peculiar to the prosecution of the fishery, and
the impossibility of replacing them at the remote harbors usually frequented,
it must be remembered that of all ships, whailing vessels are the most exposed to
accidents of all kinds, and especially to the destruction and loss of the very
things upon which the success of the voyage most depends. Hence the spare
boats, spare spars, and spare lines and harpoons, and spare everything's almost
but a spare captain and duplicate ship.
At the period of our arrival at the island, the heaviest storage of the
Peekquad had been almost completed, comprising her beef, bread, water, fuel,
and iron hoops and staves. But as before hinted, for some time there was a
continual fetching and carrying on board, of diverse odds and ends of
things, both large and small.
Chief among those who did this fetching and carrying, was Captain Bildad's
sister, a lean old lady of a most determined and inddehaticable spirit,
but with all very kind-hearted, who seemed resolved that if she could help
it, nothing should be found wanting in the Peekquad, after once fairly getting
to see. At one time she would come on board with a jar of pickles for the
steward's pantry. Another time with a bunch of quills for the chief mate's
desk where he kept his log. A third time with a roll of flannel for the small of
someone's rumatic back. Never did any woman better deserve her name which was
charity. Aunt Charity as everyone called her. And like a sister of charity did
this charitable aunt Charity bustle about hither and thither, ready to turn
her hand and heart to anything that promised to yield safety, comfort, and
consolation to all on board a ship in which her beloved brother Bildad was
concerned, and in which she herself owned a score or two of well-saved dollars.
But it was startling to see this excellent-hearted Quakerus coming on
board, as she did the last day, with a long oil ladle in one hand, and a still
longer wailing lance in the other. Nor was Bildad himself, nor Captain Pelleg
at all backward. As for Bildad, he carried about with him a long list of
the articles needed, and at every fresh arrival, down went his mark opposite
that article upon the paper. Every once in a while, Pelleg came hobbling out of
his whale bone den, roaring at the men down the hatchways, roaring up to the
riggers at the mast head, and then concluding by roaring back into his wigwam.
During these days of preparation, Quiqu and I often visited the craft, and as
often I asked about Captain Ahab, and how he was, and when he was going to
come on board his ship. to these questions they would answer that he was
getting better and better and was expected aboard every day. Meantime the
two captains, Pelleg and Bildad, could attend to everything necessary to fit
the vessel for the voyage. If I had been downright honest with myself, I would
have seen very plainly in my heart, that I did but half fancy being committed
this way to so long a voyage, without once laying my eyes on the man who was
to be the absolute dictator of it so soon as the ship sailed out upon the
open sea. But when a man suspects any wrong, it sometimes happens that if he
be already involved in the matter, he insensibly strives to cover up his
suspicions even from himself. And much this way it was with me. I said nothing
and tried to think nothing. At last it was given out that sometime next day the
ship would certainly sail. So next morning Qui Quag and I took a very early start.